Kingdom Lwandle

Johannesburg 🔒

+27727696646 📞

Kingdomlwandle@gmail.com ✓

https:/www.linkedin.com/in/king- In lwandle-76019aa0

Twitter/Blog/Portfolio

A very committed UI/UX Developer with 3 years' experience looking for my next move in the Information Technology sector. Highly focused with a comprehensive knowledge of developing the layout, visual appearance, and usability of a website. Eager to learn, easy going by nature and able to get along with both work colleagues and managers

Skills

- UI/UX development
- HTML5
- Bootstrap 4
- JavaScript
- Elementor
- PHP
- Git

- jQuery
- CS Cart
- CSS3
- WordPress
- Responsive Design
- Agile
- Google Analytics
- SEO

Experience

15 MARCH 2021 - PRESENT

Website Manager / Interfoto (9 months Contract)

TECHNOLOGIES: Html5, Bootstrap 4, WordPress, Elementor, jQuery, JavaScript, css3, Afrihost

DUTIES:

- Translating UI/UX design into html, css, javascript websites.
- Building websites from scratch.
- Updating and maintaining existing websites.
- Building eCommerce sites using WordPress and WooCommerce.
- Styling and managing all websites.
- Making sure that all the websites are responsive and compatible with all browsers.
- Testing, debugging, and hosting of all websites.

13 JULY 2020 - 13 JAN 2021

FRONT END DEVELOPER UI/UX / We Are Machine(Contract)

TECHNOLOGIES: Html5, Bootstrap 4, WordPress, Elementor, jQuery, JavaScript, css3, Apache, Mysql, Bitbucket.

DUTIES:

- Translating UI/UX design into html, css, javascript websites.
- Building websites from scratch.
- Updating and maintaining existing websites.
- Building eCommerce sites using WordPress and WooCommerce.
- Styling and managing all websites.
- Making sure that all the websites are responsive and compatible with all browsers.
- Testing, debugging, and hosting of all websites.

Reason for leaving:

Contract completed successfully.

MARCH 2019 - APRIL 2020

FRONT END DEVELOPER / My Bucks(Contract)

TECHNOLOGIES: Html5, Ajax, Sass, Less, Vue.js, Jquery, css3, Bootstrap4, Responsive design, JavaScript, Web development, WordPress, Bitbucket, Rest Api

DUTIES:

- Translating UI/UX design into html, css, javascript websites.
- Building websites from scratch.
- Updating and maintaining existing websites.
- Building eCommerce sites using WordPress and WooCommerce.
- Styling and managing all websites.
- Making sure that all the websites are responsive and compatible with all browsers.
- Testing, debugging, and hosting of all websites.

Reason for leaving:

• Contract completed successfully.

FEB 2018 - FEB 2019

WEB DEVELOPER / Hybrid Holdings

TECHNOLOGIES: Git, Html5, Laravel, jQuery, css3, bootstrap4, php ,MySQL, Responsive design, UI developer, JavaScript, Visual Studio, Vue.js,

DUTIES:

- Translating UI/UX design into html, css, javascript websites.
- Building websites from scratch.
- Updating and maintaining existing websites.
- Building eCommerce sites using WordPress and WooCommerce.
- Styling and managing all websites.
- Making sure that all the websites are responsive and compatible with all browsers.
- Testing, debugging, and hosting of all websites.

Reason for leaving:

• Company went into liquidation.

FROM AUGUST 2016 – AUGUST 2017 I TOOK A 12 MONTHS JAVA FOR BEGINNERS COURSE AND COMPLETED IT.

JAN 2015 - NOVEMBER 2016

WEB DEVELOPER / Cojedi (Internship)

TECHNOLOGIES: HTML5, CSS3, JAVASCRIPT, BOOTSTRAP, PHP AND MYSQL.

DUTIES:

- Translating UI/UX design into html, css, javascript websites.
- Building websites from scratch.
- Updating and maintaining existing websites.
- Building eCommerce sites using WordPress and WooCommerce.
- Styling and managing all websites.
- Making sure that all the websites are responsive and compatible with all browsers.
- Testing, debugging, and hosting of all websites.

Reason for leaving:

Contract completed successfully.

IN 2014 I WAS VOLUNTEERING AT BARBERTON METHODIST CHURCH AS A WEB DEVELOPER. IN 2013 I WAS DOING MY FINAL YEAR IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY AND GRADUATED.

JAN 2012 - DECEMBER 2012

PHP DEVELOPER / Mpilende foods pty ltd (Inservice training)

TECHNOLOGIES: HTML5, CSS3, JAVASCRIPT, BOOTSTRAP, PHP AND MYSQL.

DUTIES:

 Building a website and a stock inventory system for Mpilende foods. Ensuring responsiveness and compatibility of the website.

Reason for leaving:

3

• Contract completed successfully

Education

2010 - 2013

National diploma: Information technology / Durban University of Technology

2003 - 2007

Matric/ Hoerskool Barberton